{
  "id": "IIKG3020-Kahoot-2025",
  "title": "Kahoot IIKG3020 (2025) â€” Multiple choice questions (19 points)",
  "description": "Multiple Choice Questions from the wrap up kahoot in 2025. Use for practice and self-testing.",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which of these actions is NOT a containment, eradication or recovery action?",
      "choices": [
        "reporting the incidentreporting the incident",
        "removing malwareremoving malware",
        "identify vulnerabilities that were exploitedidentify vulnerabilities that were exploited",
        "confirm that the affected systems are functioning normally"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of these CSIRT services is a proactive service?",
      "choices": [
        "vulnerability handlingvulnerability handling",
        "technology watch",
        "alerts and warningsalerts and warnings",
        "artifact analysis"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 1
    },
    {
      "question": "what is an example of an atomic indicator?",
      "choices": [
        "IP address",
        "Hash value",
        "IDS rule",
        "Regular expression"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "in what phase in the intrusion kill chain model is antivirus a useful course of action?",
      "choices": [
        "Reconnaissance",
        "Exploitation",
        "Installation",
        "Command and Control"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "which of these incident indicators is an example of a definite indicator of an incident?",
      "choices": [
        "Attack reported by a user",
        "Notification from IDPS",
        "Use of dormant accounts",
        "Unusual system crashes"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "which of these threat intelligence categories is more detailed and most useful in the short term?",
      "choices": [
        "Strategic",
        "Operational",
        "Tactical",
        "Technical"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "which of these threat actors has the highest sophistication and resource level?",
      "choices": [
        "Hacktivist",
        "Crime syndicate",
        "Nation state",
        "Insider"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "Which command and control channel was most commonly used by APT1?",
      "choices": [
        "Encoded HTML comments",
        "Watering hole attacks",
        "Trojanized software downloads",
        "Stenography"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "which of these indicators of compromise will cause the attacker most pain when you respond to it?",
      "choices": [
        "TTPs",
        "Tools",
        "Domain names",
        "IP addresses"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "what comes first of these actions in the incident response life cycle?",
      "choices": [
        "Preparation",
        "Detection and analysis",
        "Containment, eradication and recovery",
        "Post-incident activity"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "Which CSIRT organizational model describes a team that serves a constituency belonging to other organizations?",
      "choices": [
        "Internal distributed CSIRT",
        "Internal centralized CSIRT",
        "Internal combined distributed and centralized CSIRT",
        "Coordinating CSIRT"
        ],
        "answerIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What list maintained by MITRE describes common software security weakness types?",
      "choices": [
        "CWE",
        "CVSS",
        "CVS",
        "CVE"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "which tool is used for monitoring files for unauthorized access?",
      "choices": [
        "Signature-based NIDPS",
        "Anomaly-based NIDPS",
        "Honeytokens",
        "Network-based IDPS"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "What is at the base of the hierarchy of needs for IR?",
      "choices": [
        "Inventory",
        "Telemetry",
        "Detection",
        "Triage"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "what is the most important step you can do to prepare to respond to a ransomware incident?",
      "choices": [
        "Coordinating with Internet Service Provider",
        "User awareness programs",
        "Use antivirus software",
        "Maintain functional backups"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 3
    },
    {
      "question": "How can passive DNS be used in incident response?",
      "choices": [
        "Discover associations among threat actors, track and block their activity",
        "For sharing of indicators between CSIRTs to implement better IDS signatures",
        "Anonymizing of IP addresses before uploading samples to Virus Total",
        "As a sandbox for dynamic malware analysis"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "what is the goal for the defender when using the cyber kill chain model?",
      "choices": [
        "Stop the intrusion further down the kill chain",
        "Implement courses of action right of hack",
        "Move the detection and analysis up the kill chain",
        "Stop the intrusion left of hack"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 2
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the distinction between an ATT&CK technique and an IOC?",
      "choices": [
        "Many ATT&CK techniques are legitimate system functions, while IOCs are notMany ATT&CK techniques are legitimate system functions, while IOCs are not",
        "ATT&CK techniques cannot be used as input to intrusion detection signatures",
        "IOCs have less utility for defenders",
        "IOCs are less dependent on specific malware or hacker tools"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 0
    },
    {
      "question": "What is DETT&CT?",
      "choices": [
        "An update to ATT&CK, developed by MITRE",
        "A framework assisting blue teams to map their detection coverage to ATT&CK",
        "A scoring system for implementation of ATT&CK IDS signatures",
        "The red team version of ATT&CK"
      ],
      "answerIndex": 1
    }
  ]
}